SYED ASIF M.N



Syedasifm.n@gmail.com \$\frac{\lambda}{\sigma}\$ +918123081213 \$\begin{align*} \text{www.linkedin.com/in/syed-asif-mn } \frac{\lambda}{\sigma}\$ https://syed-asif.vercel.app/

PROFILE SUMMARY

With four years of industry experience at the intersection of product, growth, and data, focused on developing accessible, human-centered products. Recognized for a creative and collaborative approach, strong sense of responsibility, and meticulous attention to detail, while driving innovative solutions.

SKILLS

- Web: Angular, React, Streamlit, JS, HTML, CSS
- Backend: C#, .NET, Flask, Python, Node
- Databases: MySQL, MongoDB
- Cloud: AWS, Azure DevOps
- Containerization: Docker
- Data Processing: Apache Spark, Kafka
- Data Visualization: Microsoft Power BI

EDUCATION

P.G certificate in Software Engineering for Data Science, 2022 - 2023

International Institute of Information Technology, Hyderabad

B.E In Electronics and Communication, 2016 - 2020 JSS Science and Technology University, Mysuru. CGPA: 9.13/10

PUBLICATIONS

Indoor Navigation Assistant for Visually Impaired (INAVI)

International Conference on Communication, Computing and Electronics Systems.

https://doi.org/10.1007/978-981-33-4909-4_17

SPECIALIZATIONS AND CERTIFICATIONS

- Data Structures & Algorithms Udacity
- Foundations of Front-End Web Development Udemy
- ES6 Udacity
- AWS Machine Learning Foundations 2022 Udacity
- Final Exam: Scrum Product Owner Skillsoft
- The Bible of Competitive Programming Udemy
- Al on cloud Great Learning
- Deep Learning DeepLearning.ai
- IoT and Embedded Systems Workshop Keonics

EXTRA CURRICULUM

- Awarded 'Star of the Sprints 2024' for professional contributions.
- Winner: IIITH, PGCSEDS Hackathon (2022). Finalist: Hackerearth Aerothon (2023)
- Volunteer: 'Save The Child' NGO, 'Project Rise' NGO (2018-20), SHPL Veteran ERG.
- Served as school head and college head.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Design And Development Engineer, Siemens Healthineers September 2020 - Present

- Implemented modular architecture for OSD Configurator and PED subsystems for ARTIS product line using Node, Angular (Typescript) with NgRx library.
- Developed and maintained Solution-level Defects/Metrics/Feature Analytics Data reports. Tech stack: Python, Azure Services, Microsoft Power BI, MS Excel.
- Contributed to .NET server code with MySQL integration via Fluent NHibernate.
- Automated server and client SSIT using Selenium and Specflow (BDD).
- Involved in cross-functional team discussions and contributed to specifications documentation using Enterprise Architect, SAP and Polarion.
- Skilled in designing and implementing Azure CI/CD build pipelines.
- Proficient in Scaled Agile methodologies and clean code principles.
- Mentoring team by conducting workshops and knowledge transfer sessions.
- Developed 'Brain AVM Analyzer' algorithm using U-Net Deep learning model.

Intern, Siemens Healthineers

January 2020 - May 2020

 Automated On Screen display subsystem using C#, Python and Selenium, reducing manual testing efforts by about 90%

PROJECTS

Voter-CRM /Voter-CRM

Web application for IIITH's Voter CRM Project. Tech & Tools: AWS, Ubuntu, Streamlit.

unfold.stackblitz.io

An open-source full-stack code generator. Tech & Tools: Angular, Django, MySQL.

best best-lyrics.stackblitz.io

Minimal UI for curated English song lyrics. Tech & Tools: ReactJS, Glitch.

Solar System Tour planets-gsap.vercel.app

Supported for Desktops. Tech & Tools: Vercel, GSAP, JS, HTML, CSS3.

Periodic Table elements-table.vercel.app

Tech & Tools: Angular 8, Node.

E-Commerce Firm Data Analysis /data-analysis-with-MongoDB

Tech & Tools: MongoDB, Compass

IOT Devices Data Analysis /iot-devices-data-analysis

Tech & Tools: Spark SQL.

Explainable AI using H2O /explainable-AI-using-H2O

Explainability of different H2O bike rental prediction models. Tech & Tools: H2O, Kaggle

PCA and LDA /pca-and-lda

/RSA-for-signature-verification

High dimensional data analysis with PCA and LDA. Tech & Tools: Pandas, SkLearn, Seaborn

RSA for Signature Verification Tech & Tools: Kaggle, pycryptodome

Explore all my projects on GitHub: https://github.com/syed-asif-mn